JUNAID YOUNUS

7X Salesforce Certified – Salesforce Marketing Cloud Expert

GitHub/junaidyounus • LinkedIn/junaidsoomro • +92333-2363848 • soomroj24@gmail.com

PROFILE

Talented software programmer, strong background in programming and experience using cuttingedge development tools. Articulate and professional communication skills, including formal presentations and technical documentation. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects; dedicated to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge and IT skills.

Knowledge & Skill Areas:

Lightning Web Component, Flow, Apex Development, AMPScript, AMP Email HTML, CSS & JavaScript, WordPress

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

Languages: SQL Developer, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Salesforce Apex, LWC

Tools: Salesforce CRM, Salesforce Marketing Cloud, Oracle Forms & Reports Development.

EXPERIENCE

Merkle Australia

Augmentation Salesforce Consultant (March 2023 to Present)

- Working with the SFMC team to create discovery of the Interaction Studio project.
- Building Emails and content blocks
- Upload the asset in the specified folder of SFMC.
- Used AMPScript for personalizing the emails and landing page content.
- Create the solution documentation related to the project gueries.
- Create LWC component for getting modern and smooth UI.
- Manage approval request with approval process.
- Build Flows for complex business uses cases.

Aware Services Pty. Ltd

Augmentation Salesforce Consultant (June 2022 to February 2023)

- Working with SFMC team on the several use cases of Salesforce Personalization.
- Help the team to build the sitemap and design by using best practices.
- Fixed the issues and updated web template configure as per client requirement.
- Created the segmentation for specific use cases.
- Created real time interaction of customer with open time email campaign.
- Configured catalog objects and attributes.
- Take analysis by using segmentations and use these segments into journey for real time engagement.
- Go through the documentation to integrate SFMC email instead of Calendly notification.
- Used AMPScript for update and retrieve Salesforce Objects data for emails.

Workflow Hub Pvt. Ltd

Salesforce Marketing Cloud Developer (December 2020 to Present)

- Experience using Journey Builder with the ability to build more complex journeys for common use cases.
- Supported the email marketing team with building custom queries, AmpScript based dynamic templates, automation jobs, and built out comprehensive customer journeys.
- Understood business requirements and delivering high quality technical solutions that empower the Marketing teams to utilize the Marketing Cloud automation platform.
- Create and maintain Lists, Data Extensions, and subscriber lists.
- Tracked communications.
- Developed relevant reports and dashboards.

- Developed form data collection from Landing pages to DE.
- Provide email open/click/bounce analysis as the report to client.

Marine Knight Export Pvt. Ltd Salesforce Administrator (February 2020 to August 2020)

- Designed, set up, and maintained Salesforce standard objects, custom objects, and junction objects.
- Created and updated users, reports, and dashboards to track pipeline stages for management visibility while integrating Apex applications with Salesforce accounts, such as Conga Merge and Outlook
- Conducted user and administration training sessions to help clients utilize Salesforce and respective programs.
- Developed reports, dashboards, and processes to continuously monitor data quality and integrity.
- Managed the database for the team's regions and performed basic administration, deduping, and cleanup procedures Managed ongoing support requests and the administrative needs of users.
- Monitored teams' adoption rates and responded as needed, providing them with training sessions, communication, and documentation.
- I appreciate the opportunity to bring my passion and problem-solving abilities to Charter Sales, as well as the chance to make a difference in how you do business.

Internship at Innovative Channels Pvt. Ltd. Oracle Reports & Forms Developer (May 2019 to January 2020)

- Developed several in-house software on reports and forms bases.
- Designed and developed regulatory and statistical reports.
- Basic database procedures
- Maintaining Integrated Management System providing high quality of new forms and reports
- Maintaining and modifying web applications

CERTIFICATION

- Salesforce Certified Administrator (August 2020)
- Marketing Cloud Personalization Accredited Professional (Interaction Studio) (January 2023)
- Salesforce Marketing Cloud Email Specialist (January 2023)
- Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I (March 2023)
- Salesforce Certified Marketing Cloud Administrator (March 2023)
- Salesforce Certified Associate (May 2023)
- Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder (October 2023)

EDUCATION

- Bachelor of Arts (2018)
 Federal Urdu University Arts, Science and Technology, Karachi.
- Advance Certified Computer Professional Software Development (2014 2018) Aptech Computer Center, Karachi.

^{*}References and additional Information will gladly be provided upon request